## **Robert Farley, CAPM**

Tulsa, OK • 5702096717 • rfarley89@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/robertfarley89 • github.com/Nomad-Rob • NomadRob.com

## **Project Manager**

Seasoned Project Manager with a diverse background in software engineering, aviation, and military/law enforcement operations. Expierenced at leading cross-functional teams, managing complex hardware and software deployments, and driving operational efficiencies using Agile & Scrum methodologies. Experienced in risk assessment, stakeholder communication, and regulatory compliance, with a strong ability to bridge technical and operational challenges in high-stakes environments.

## **SKILLS**

- Agile/Scrum Methodologies
- API Development
- Cross-Functional Team Leadership
- · Data Collection & Analysis
- FAA Regulations
- · G Suite Proficiency

- Jira
- Power BI
- Process Improvement
- Project Scheduling & Timeline Management
- Resource Allocation & Budget Management
- Risk Management

- Risk Management & Problem Solving
- Security Practices: Cyber & Physical
- SQL & MySQL
- · Stakeholder Engagement
- Strategic Planning

- Team Building and Development
- · Technical Acumen
- Technical Communication
- Vendor & Stakeholder Management
- Web Development
- · Workflow Optimization

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Expert TA · Tulsa, OK · Nov 2024 - Present

## Implementation Specialist • Full-time

- Manages cross-functional collaboration with subject-matter experts, graphic designers, and content specialists to develop high-quality, interactive educational content.
- Performs QA testing, mitigates risks, and refines processes to improve grading precision, user experience, and engagement across 60,000+ users.
- · Analyze student interaction data to optimize homework content effectiveness and engagement.
- Supports project planning and timeline management for ongoing curriculum development initiatives.

## FlightSafety International • Tulsa, OK • May 2024 - Aug 2024

## **Software Engineer Intern**

- Led a collaborative effort to resolve anti-aliasing issues in FSI's flight simulation systems transition to Unreal Engine, managing Jira tasks and implementing cutting-edge solutions to meet FAA standards.
- Developed and led an A/B testing framework to evaluate and grade various anti-aliasing methods, ensuring data-driven decisions that optimized visual quality.
- Coordinated with IT teams and vendors to implement an anti-aliasing solution, improving visual geometry accuracy by 10%

# **Oklahoma Army National Guard •** Tulsa, OK • Jun 2020 - Oct 2023 **Helicopter Pilot UH60M**

- Executed over 100 successful flight missions, utilizing advanced flight planning, navigation, and system management skills.
- Managed large-scale projects involving technical systems integration and team coordination, ensuring compliance with high standards.
- Led a biannual, multi-day Flight Operations inspection, achieving a passing score above 90% across more than 80 evaluated criteria.

## Aeqis/ GardaWorld Federal Services • Afghanistan • On-site • May 2019 - May 2020

## **Designated Defensive Marksman**

- Streamlined protective security operations for Department of State personnel, achieving a 14% increase in procedural efficiency through detailed data reviews and security enhancements.
- Utilized data analysis and real-time information systems to evaluate mission environments and provide actionable intelligence for decision-making.

## Oklahoma Army National Guard • On-site • Nov 2006 - May 2020

## **Sniper/Scout Platoon Sergeant**

 Advanced proficiency in using mathematical models and calculations for trajectory prediction, range estimation, and environmental factor analysis. Spearheaded deployment of 40 Sniper and Scout soldiers, resulting in successful completion of multiple joint operations.

# **Oklahoma Counterdrug Task Force** • Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, United States · On-site • Feb 2016 - May 2019 **Ground Reconnaissance Team Leader/Project Lead**

- Led the establishment of a high-performing team for the State of Oklahoma by defining mission objectives, recruiting skilled professionals, and fostering a collaborative team culture, resulting in a newly developed Ground Recon Team.
- Managed large-scale projects involving technical systems integration, ensuring compliance with military standards while reducing operational errors for the state and staying within our program budget of \$1.8 million.
- Built and maintained relationships with federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies to facilitate successful mission outcomes, fostering collaborative environments.

# **Xerox Business Solutions Southwest** • Yukon, Oklahoma, United States · On-site • Feb 2015 - Feb 2016 **Senior Technical Supervisor**

- Led a team of 20, boosting resolution efficiency by 25% through strategic management and innovative problem-solving in technical support operations.
- Managed the digital asset system and collaborated with external vendors to ensure accurate delivery and invoicing for all
  creative assets.

### **EDUCATION**

## Diploma - Computer Science & Full-Stack Web Development

Atlas School · Jan 2023 - Aug 2024

Student Life Committee Vice Chair

#### **VOLUNTEERING & LEADERSHIP**

#### **Techlahoma**

- Volunteered at 2023 ThunderPlains Conference to support the logistics of the check in process for over 200 individuals.
- Involved with setting up Oklahoma's first state-wide Hackathon 2024

### Atlas School

Led biannual alumni events, successfully managing a \$6,000 budget to foster community engagement and networking.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM) · Aug 2024

Google Project Management, Cybersecurity Professional, AI Essentials • Jun 2024 - Aug 2024